[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：但最小权力原则是有希望的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But there is hope in the principle of least authority.
它告诉我们，任何软件单元都应该具有这样的能力
Which teaches that any unit of software should be given just the capability
因为它需要做它的工作，而不是更多。
as it needs to do its work and no more.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：能力可以在Actor模型中看到，
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Capabilities can be seen in the Actor model,
这是1973年在麻省理工学院发现的。
which was discovered at MIT in 1973.
对演员模型的研究导致了Scheme的发明，
The investigation of the Actor model led to the invention of Scheme,
这导致了更高阶的函数和所有的好东西。
which led to higher order functions and all that good stuff.
它也会导致演员。
It also lead to Actors.
因此在Actor模型中，参与者是一个计算实体。
So in the Actor model, an actor is a computational entity.
这就像异步对象系统。
It's like asynchronous object systems.
参与者只有在知道其地址时才能向另一个参与者发送消息。
An actor can send a message to another actor only if it knows its address.
参与者可以创建新参与者，参与者可以创建消息。
An actor can create a new actor and an actor can create messages.
Web工作者有点像参与者，Web服务不是，但应该是。
Web workers are kind of like actors web services aren't but should.
有一个叫Waterken的系统
There is a system called Waterken that was
由HP实验室开发，该实验室将After模型应用于Web服务。
developed at HP Labs, which applies the after model to web services.
我认为这个东西很棒，它给你提供了非常可靠的系统。
I think the stuff is brilliant, it gives you very reliable systems.
我强烈建议进入这一领域。
I highly recommend getting into that.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这就是演员所做的事情之一
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: And so one of the things that comes out of the the Actor
模型是能力的概念。
model is the idea of capabilities.
所以对参与者的地址是一种能力，或者对一个对象的引用是一种能力。
So an address to an actor is a capability or reference to an object is a capability.
所以让我们将功能应用于面向对象编程，
So let's apply capabilities to object-oriented programming,
查看对象功能。
looking at object capabilities.
这是一个物体。
So here is an object.
A是一个对象，它有状态和行为。
A is an object, it has state and behavior.
对象A具有对象B的引用，因为对象可以具有引用。
Object A has a reference to object B because objects can have references.
对象A可以与对象B通信，因为它具有该引用。
Object A can communicate with Object B because it has that reference.
对象B提供了一个接口，该接口将访问限制为它自己的状态
Object B provides an interface that constrains access to its own state in
参考资料。
references.
所以对象A不能访问B的内部，只能访问它的接口。
So object A does not get access to B's internals, only to its interface.
这就是为什么我喜欢在JavaScript中冻结。
This is why I like freezing in JavaScript.
因为在JavaScript中，这是保证这一点的唯一方法。
Because in JavaScript, that is the only way to guarantee this.
做好可靠物品的唯一方法。
The only way to make good reliable objects.
对象A没有对C的引用，因此A无法与C通信。
Object A does not have a reference to C, so A cannot communicate with C.
就好像在A和A之间有一道防火墙
It's as though there is a firewall between A and
C期望防火墙是零成本实施的。
C expect that firewall is implemented at zero cost.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：通过约束产生对象能力系统
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: An object capability system is produced by constraining
参考文献的获取方式。
the ways that references are obtained.
不能简单地通过知道公共对象的名称来获得引用
A reference cannot be obtained simply by knowing the name of a public
全局变量或公共类的。
of a global variable or a public class.
实际上，有三种方法可以通过创造来获得引用，
And in fact, there are exactly three ways to obtain a reference by creation,
通过建造和引进。
by construction, and by introduction.
通过创建意味着如果函数创建对象
By creation means that if a function creates an object
它获取对该对象的引用。
it gets a reference to that object.
通过构造意味着对象可以由其构造函数赋予
By construction means that an object may be endowed by its constructor
还有参考资料。
with references.
这可以包括构造函数上下文中的引用和
This can include references in the constructors context and
继承的引用。
inherited references.
然后3，这是一个有趣的介绍。
And then 3, this is the interesting one by introduction.
所以这里A引用了B和C。
So here A has references to B and C.
B和C没有引用，因此它们无法通信。
B and C have no references, so they cannot communicate.
但是A希望他们能够沟通。
But A wants them to be able to communicate.
所以A和B通信。
So A communicates with B.
将引用传递给C，一旦完成，
Passing a reference to C, and once that is done,
B现在已经获得了与C通信的能力。
B has now acquired the capability to communicate with C.
这就是为什么这被称为能力模型。
That's why this is called the capability model.
如果引用只能通过创建来获得，
If references can only be obtained by creation,
建设，或介绍，那么你可能有一个安全的系统。
construction, or introduction, then you may have a safe system.
如果它们可以通过任何其他方式获得，你就不能。
And if they can be obtained in any other way, you don't.
所以要注意的潜在弱点包括强奸，
So potential weaknesses to watch out for include arrogation,
腐败，混乱和串通。
corruption, confusion, and collusion.
侵占是指无权利地夺取或要求自己的权利。
Arrogation means to take or claim for oneself without right.
这包括全局变量，公共静态变量，
This include global variables, public static variables,
授予强大功能的标准库，地址生成。
standard libraries that grant powerful capabilities, address generation.
这就是为什么C+永远不能像Web系统中的语言和已知URL那样安全。
Which is why C++ can never be as secure a language and known URLs in web systems.
腐败，应该不能篡改或
Corruption, It should not be possible to tamper with or
绕过系统或其他对象。
circumvent the system or other objects.
再说一次，这就是为什么冰冻是如此重要的原因。
Again, that's why the freezing is so critically important.
第三个困惑，
Number 3 confusion,
应该可以创建不受混淆的对象。
it should be possible to create objects that are not subject to confusion.
因为混淆的对象可能被欺骗，然后滥用其功能。
Because a confused object can be tricked, and then misusing its capabilities.
然后，终于串通了。
And then, finally collusion.
在引入两个对象之前，它们必须是不可能通信的。
It must not be possible for two objects to communicate until they are introduced.
如果两个独立对象结束，
If two independent objects conclude,
他们也许能够集中他们的能力来造成伤害。
they might be able to pool their capabilites to cause harm.
有些功能太危险，不能提供给来宾代码。
Some capabilities are too dangerous to give to guest code.
因此，我们可以将这些功能提供给中间对象，这些中间对象将
So we can instead give those capabilities to intermediate objects that will
限制他们的力量。
constrain their power.
例如，用于
For example, an intermediate object for
文件系统可能会限制对特定设备或目录等的访问。
a file system might limit access to a particular device or directory or so on.
最终，每个对象都应该被赋予与其完全相同的功能
Ultimately, every object should be given exactly the capabilities it
需要做它的工作而不是更多。
needs to do its work and no more.
因此，应该在需要做的基础上授予能力
So capability should be granted on a need-to-do basis
就像我们在需要知道的基础上提供信息一样。
just as we grant information on a need-to-know basis.
我们所知道的信息隐藏的原则导致了良好的设计和
The principles of information hiding, which we know leads to good designs and
当你考虑能力隐藏时，软件系统得到了增强。
software systems, are enhanced when you're thinking about capability hiding.
中间对象或facet可以是非常轻量级的。
Intermediate objects or facets can be very lightweight.
并且无类语言可能特别有效。
And class-free languages can be especially effective.
我尝试过用Java制作facet，结果发现，这真的很难，因为每个
I've tried making facets in Java and it turns out, it's really hard because every
当你想做一个小连接器的时候，你必须做另一个类。
time you wanna make a little connector, you have to make another class.
这是很大的工作量。
And that's a lot of work.
而在JavaScript中，这些东西大多只是一个简单的对象或
Whereas in JavaScript, most of these things are just a simple object or
发电机，砰，你完蛋了。
generator and, boom, you're done.
因此，在这里，facet对象限制Guest对象对功能强大的对象的访问。
So here the Facet object limits the Guest object's access to a powerful object.
Guest对象不能篡改facet以获取直接
The Guest object cannot tamper with the Facet to get a direct
对危险对象的引用。
reference to the dangerous object.
引用在能力系统中是不可撤销的，
References are not revocable in a capability system,
一旦你介绍了一个对象，你就不能要求它忘记它。
once you introduce an object, you can't ask it to forget it.
你可以要求，但你不能依赖于请求被尊重。
You can ask but you can not depend on the request being honored.
因此这里Guest对象有一个对Agency对象的引用。
So here the Guest object has a reference to an Agency object.
客人要求
The Guest asks for
介绍强大的对象，&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：但是
an introduction to the powerful object, &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: But
相反，中情局做了一个方面，
the Agency instead makes a Facet and
将facet提供给Guest，facet可能是一个简单的直通。
gives the Facet to the Guest and the Facet might be a simple pass through.
然后Guest可以调用facet，pass。
The Guest can then call the Facet, the pass.
然后它将调用强大的对象。
It will then call the powerful object.
当中情局想要撤销这项能力时，
When the Agency wants to revoke the capability,
它告诉facet忘记它的能力。
it tells the Facet to forget its capability.
facet现在对来宾没有用处了。
The Facet is now useless to the guest.
这就是你昨天所做的。
This is what you did yesterday.
昨天可撤销的功能是这个模式，所以
Yesterday's revocable function was this pattern, so
这些东西真的很容易实现。
these things are really easy to implement.
facet可以将请求标记为
A Facet can mark requests so
强大的物体可以知道它们来自哪里。
that the Powerful object can know where they came from.
这给了我们责任。
That gives us accountability.
facet是非常有表现力的，它们很容易构造，它们是轻量级的。
Facets are very expressive, they're easy to construct, they're lightweight.
它们提供衰减或功率降低。
They provide attenuation or power reduction.
他们给我们撤销，通知，授权。
They give us revocation, notification, delegation.
事实证明，最好的面向对象模式也是功能模式。
And it turns out the best object-oriented patterns are also capabilities patterns.
有时当你试图设计一个系统
Sometimes when you're trying to design a system and
你想弄清楚这种能力是去那里还是去那里？
you're trying to figure out does this capability go there or there?
而且在早期对它们进行分类，当你在设计分类法时是很困难的。
And sorting those early on in, when you're doing that design a taxonomy is hard.
但如果你从能力的角度考虑，最小的是什么
But if you think about it in terms of capabilities, what is the least
我需要给这个家伙多少能量才能让它正常工作？
amount of power I need to give to this guy in order to have it work correctly?
你往往会得到正确的设计。
You tend to end up with the correct designs.
对安全性的考虑使系统设计更容易，而不是更难。
That thinking about security make system designing easier not harder.
所以镶嵌面可以降低危险物体的威力。
So Facets can reduce the power of dangerous objects.
大多数代码不应该被授予直接访问危险事物的权限，因为
Most code should not be given directly access to dangerous things, for
例如浏览器innerHTML或document.write。
example the browser innerHTML or document.write.
不是试图猜测一段代码是否可以做坏事，
Instead of trying to guess if a piece of code can do something bad,
相反，我们可以给它一组安全的功能。
we can give it a safe set of capabilities instead.
你知道，即使它是坏的，它所能做的也是有限的。
You know that even if it is bad, it's limited in what it can do.
并且功能可以帮助API设计。
And capabilities can aid in API design.